<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts on garybuckle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Posts on garybuckle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Via Claudia Augusta Tour 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/via-claudia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/via-claudia/</guid>
      <description>Via Claudia Augusta - The Start Some time ago a good friend of mine told me that his dream was to cycle from Bavaria in southern Germany, across the alps and finish at Lake Garda in Italy, along a route called Via Claudia Augusta. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but I said I would love to do it too, I&amp;rsquo;m not even…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London2Brighton:down and dirty!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/l2b2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/l2b2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Once you descend into that dark place out on the trail, where everything is crashing down around you, you need to find something real to keep you moving. It could be love or pain, but it has to be real. It certainly won’t be Facebook likes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We travelled over by train on Friday evening, meeting up with Sean at St Pancras at around 7:30. He was a bit knackered, we were a bit knackered so we opted out of meeting up and eating together. Heike and I were in Richmond town centre so we found an Italian restaurant and took our seats outside. To our left, 2 blokes kitted out for what seemed like a long run and to our left and elderly woman who we had previously passed limping along the street. The fit blokes were obviously doing the L2B and I eavesdropped a bit. Not their first ultra but definitely their first 100km. They discussed future events pending their success on Saturday. I demolished spinach ravioli, two bottles of sparkling water and an espresso affogato. The lady on our right finished at approximately the same time as us and as she rose I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but notice a t-shirt adorned with the Jurassic coast 100km ultra logo. Aha! She was also doing the L2B. As she passed I wished her good luck. She thanked me and asked me if I too was running, I told her it was my first time and that I was running with my son who&amp;rsquo;d run it last year. She wished me luck and told me that she&amp;rsquo;d run the Jurassic coast 100km a week earlier. I was genuinely speechless and told her so. &amp;ldquo;Oh it&amp;rsquo;s nothing at all, I do them all the time. I&amp;rsquo;m not fast but I just keep going&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London to Brighton- the preparation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/london2brighton-prequel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/london2brighton-prequel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Devil whispered in my ear: ‘You’re not strong enough to withstand the storm.’ I whispered back: ‘I am the storm&amp;rsquo;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture above is my son Sean Buckle who ran a 100km from London to Brighton this time last year. He never stopped smiling! This year he has convinced me to run it with him. I&amp;rsquo;ve run one Ultra before and if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what an Ultra is then I asked ChatGPT for you and&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berlin blow for blow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/berlin2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/berlin2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Berlin2023&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/berlin-blow-for-blow.avif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked across a former airfield, the wind in our faces, surrounded by cyclists, skateboarders and runners. This was marathon day minus 1, Saturday, registration day. Eventually we found the entrance to the Berlin marathon registration expo, heavily sponsored by, no let’s not mention the sponsors. Without them it wouldn’t happen but they got enough airtime. Colleen and I made our way through the myriad of checks, id and marathon pass shananigans, funnelled through to the registration counter. Berlin is funny, I’m never sure which language I should be using. Everyone starts with English and because I don’t wanna be a tourist, I answer in German, they reply in English and the game continues. Anyway, everything goes smoothly and we get our tracking chips (No salt and Vinegar) and number bibs. Finally we meet up with our support team, Heike and Alicia, we make our way out and home. But not before buying some merch and chatting to the antipodean scientist at the Super Sapiens stand. We discuss the future of sport, nutrition and pretty much everything. He was a pretty switched on bloke and I wish I had gotten his email.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The final countdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/final-countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/final-countdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The reason we race isn&amp;rsquo;t so much to beat each other,&amp;hellip; but to be with each other” — Christopher McDougall, Born to Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start towards the start line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training is over, whatever I do now is not going to significantly impact the performance in Berlin on Sunday. Meaning that if I go out and drag myself through a 21km or a fast 10km, the impact of such training wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really impact the race result on sunday. I am not absolutely sure of that though, in the past I have often tried to cram in runs in the last days. One thing is certain for me, in my head. I have done enough to get me round the course in the desired time, no point in doing anymore. What is left now is to avoid anything that might negatively impact that. For me it means no squash, no running, no alcohol and some nice walks. Squash is too explosive and would increase injury risk. Running wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help, see above and also might cause me to incur an injury. Alcohol will impact my heart rate, general health and sleep, I normally drink a lot less weeks before an event and definitely nothing a week before. Nice walks are going to make me happy, realised and expose me to the countryside. On Sunday Colleen and I are going to immerse ourselves in the Marathon. In my experience and opinion it&amp;rsquo;s the whole package, the nerves, the doubts, the crowds, the part of being involved in something. Then the performance, the various stages that you traverse through both mentally and physically. Finally of course the finish, that is for a lot of people the best bit. I cant say I don&amp;rsquo;t look forward to seeing the finish but as soon as you stop, your body realises that it&amp;rsquo;s in a bit of pain. Normally my legs cramp up badly and although I want to sit, I can&amp;rsquo;t. Better to walk around a bit, like a zombie. The obvious thoughts about why do I do this? until the next time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berlin bound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/berlin-bound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/berlin-bound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The photo is 5 years old! In 2017 a very good friend and myself ventured to Berlin in order to run the Marathon.
5 years later I am back again but this time with &lt;a href=&#34;href=https://colleenanderhub.co.uk&#34;&gt;Colleen&lt;/a&gt; my daughter.
She is attempting her first marathon and together we are going to blast through the Brandenburg gate in around 4 hours.
Berlin is one of my favourites, as is Köln (more about that to come). T
here is very definitely an international vibe along with tte fact that you&amp;rsquo;re running on the same tarmac that &lt;a href=&#34;href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eliud_Kipchoge&#34;&gt;Eliud Kipchoge&lt;/a&gt; is running on, the current world record holder.
That&amp;rsquo;s a bit special! We have 5 weeks and 5 days left to go and Colleen is beginning to realise that those 42km are getting closer.
She&amp;rsquo;s prepared pretty well with some great runs around Berlin, she&amp;rsquo;s already pretty fit and she&amp;rsquo;s definitely streamlined.
The crowds will pull us through! The event will summon up the adrenaline, the dopamine, the endorphins and the mind and body will slide along through the streets of Berlin.
The wall, the runners wall will not be a factor because just like the Berlin wall we will pull it down! For me it&amp;rsquo;s another marathon in another great city somewhere.
I am not stopping yet. Now I am going to write about those 10 plus Köln marathons I have done. Until then &amp;hellip; keep on running!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berlin The last two weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/berlin-the-last-two-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/berlin-the-last-two-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When anyone tells me I can’t do anything, I’m just not listening anymore.” — Florence Griffith Joyner
Tapering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks to go before Berlin, personally it&amp;rsquo;s been a busy time. Our house is a Baustelle, a building site, wires hanging out of the half finished walls, everything covered in dust. Still a lot of things to do. My only escape is running but I&amp;rsquo;m not really running that much now because in two weeks myself and Colleen are taking part in the Berlin Marathon. So I am taking it easy but while I remember, Here is a bit about Colleen and her sponsorship. So officially I am tapering, there are a lot of different takes on how to taper but basically you aim to be at your peak on the day of the race. Personally I have tried a few varied approaches and honestly couldn&amp;rsquo;t say if either of them worked, it&amp;rsquo;s all very much anecdotal. So I cannot really offer any solid advice other than work it out for yourselves! Not very helpful. That said at my ripe old age I am mostly aiming not to get injured. For me it means running less, playing less squash, eating healthily and running slower or at least with a lower heart rate. Tapering for me is testing your running style, how do your legs feel? not stressing about pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sports Watch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sports-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sports-watch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received my first real wrist based sports device in 2011. A Garmin GPS watch, a gift for my 50th birthday. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve owned a few different sports watches but mainly from 3 different sources, 3 different companies. Those 3 companies listed in the chronological order of my experience are Garmin, Apple and Polar, encompassing various models and products. You can get fantastic reviews on the products from various sources and YouTube videos detailing various experiences but this is not really a review, it&amp;rsquo;s my experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running past the Katzensteine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/running-past-the-katzensteine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/running-past-the-katzensteine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-past-the-katzensteine&#34;&gt;Running past the Katzensteine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a great find, the sandstone rocks! The forest and the fact that  it is less than 3km away from where we live. I have looked up the rocks  on  &lt;a href=&#34;href=https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Katzensteine&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, they&amp;rsquo;re old, very old. I have no idea what the area is specifically called, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely on the edge of the &lt;a href=&#34;href=https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nationalpark_Eifel&#34;&gt;Eifel National Park&lt;/a&gt;.
I am slowly starting to discover how great this place is to run around.
You can see my route (one of many) on &lt;a href=&#34;href=https://www.komoot.com/tour/1070513190&#34;&gt;Komoot&lt;/a&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to share a bit of info here on my running experience around  this part of Mechernich.
I am equipped with a healthy appreciation of the beauty of the natural  surroundings, this tends to already lift my mood somewhat.
Then there  are the endorphins, they appear a few kilometers into the run.
I always  try to do at least 16km and sometimes 21km, if I am feeling extra buoyant then I will do 30km.
In addition to the endorphins and the forest I have a 21st century invention, Podcasts.
For the Katzensteine  and forest runs such as this one I have -  The  &lt;a href=&#34;href=https://play.acast.com/s/blindboy&#34;&gt;Blind Boy podcast&lt;/a&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s a classic!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running in Villewald</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/running-in-villewald/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/running-in-villewald/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-in-the-forests-of-germany&#34;&gt;Running in the forests of Germany&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I (we) arrived in Weilerswist in September, a small town outside of Cologne. I had already committed to running the Cologne Marathon and whilst training for that event I discovered the Erft. I like running alongside the banks of rivers or canals anyway but it&amp;rsquo;s flat, very flat. That said, the flatness of the Erft got me ready for the flatness of Cologne so I am not complaining. Running along the Erft though, did not feed my soul in the same way running in the forest did and still does. Linslade Woods or Rushmere being great examples. So here I am discovering Villewald on my own! It was a slow process and I logged my routes on Komoot, in fact thanks to Komoot I managed to find my way through the paths that are not shown on normal maps like google maps or apple maps. So actually I can highly recommend Komoot. Villewald is a really nice place to run, it&amp;rsquo;s not flat either and there are a few lakes to run around. Now I feel that my soul is being fed!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
